Guide to the Berkeley College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Berkeley College, Yale University, records of the master
1932-1990
RU 441
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18.75
The records consist of correspondence and administrative files documenting the students and activities of the master of Berkeley College, Yale University. Also included are Robert Triffin's records on the Yale Class of 1969 Legal Defense Fund.
Berkeley College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-C-2 (YRG 13-C-2), Records of the master of Berkeley College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence and administrative files documenting the students and activities of the master of Berkeley College, Yale University. Also included are Robert Triffin's records on the Yale Class of 1969 Legal Defense Fund.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Triffin, Robert; Berkeley College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Subject files and summer session records, 1932-1959; Accession 19ND-A-395
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  - Subject Files
    - Allocations Committee, 1937-1948 (Box 1)
    - Athletics, 1934-1948 (Box 1)
    - Athletics, Reports of W.H. Neale, 1934-1947 (Box 1)
    - Building, Berkeley College, correspondence, 1932-1934, undated (Box 1)
      General
      See also: box 3, James Gamble Rogers
    - Bulletins, Army Co. A and E, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - Bulletins, Berkeley, 1943-1945 (Box 1)
    - Bursary, correspondence, numerous files, 1934-1956, undated (Box 1)
    - Corinthian Yacht Club, 1956-1959, undated (Box 1)
    - Dean's Office, 1939-1946, undated (Box 1)
    - Directories, 1934-1953 (Box 1)
    - D'Oyly Carte Opera, 1935-1940, undated (Box 1)
    - D'Oyly Carte Opera Parties, 1935-1939, undated (Box 1)
    - Carnegie Studies in Engineering, 1952-1958 (Box 2)
    - Directed Studies, 1949-1958 (Box 2)
    - Functions, 1939-1948 (Box 2)
    - The High Street Herald, 1949-1959 (Box 2)
    - Hoyt Memorial, 1940-1948 (Box 2)
    - King's College Chapel, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Library, Berkeley College, 1939-1942 (Box 2)
    - Lohmann, Carl A., 1935-1946 (Box 2)
    - Master's House furnishings, 1934-37 (Box 2)
    - Portraits of Master's Seymour and Hemingway, 1939-1951 (Box 2)
    - Rogers, James Gamble, architect for Berkeley College, 1933, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Seymour, Charles, President, 1937-1949 (Box 3)
    - Student Office Files, 1934-1948, undated (Box 3)
      - bursary employment (Box 3)
      - various activities (Box 3)
      - Nephews of Vanessa, 1935-1959, undated (Box 3)
    - Files of deceased students, 1941-1950, undated (Box 4)
    - Berkely Players, 1960, undated (Box 4)
      - Production Files (Box 4)
    - Bishop Devils: musical arrangements, including many anonymous arrangers and Fenno Heath, 1954-1958, undated (Box 4)
  - Summer Session
    - 1946
      - Preliminary Registration cards, Yale only (Box 5)
        - Undergraduate students, A - Z (Box 5)
        - Graduates, A - Y (Box 5)
        - Geology Field Trip, H - W (Box 5)
        - Navy V-195, A - S (Box 5)
      - (Grades sent to M.A.T. Office in Graduate School), 1960 July 20 (Box 5)
        - Anticipated enrollments, 1947 February 5 (Box 5)
        - List of courses, 1946 (Box 5)
    - 1947
      - Preliminary Registration cards, Yale and Non-Yale students, A - Z (Box 6)
      - Blank grade cards (Box 6)
      - Requests for grades and transcripts, 1947-1959 (Box 6)
        - (Grades sent to M.A.T. Office in Graduate School), 1960 July 20 (Box 6)
- Records of the Legal Defense Fund, 1969-1977; Accession 1979-A-001
  The materials are open for research.
  - Class of 1969 Legal Defense Fund
    - correspondence, 1969-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - checkbook, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - bank statements, deposit slips, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - bank statements, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Records of scholarships and financial programs, 1951-1969; Accession 1987-A-037
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2045
  - Balliol College (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Ehrman Scholarship, 1951-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Focillon Fellow (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Henry Fellows (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hoyt Lectureships (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - King's College (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Oxford-Cambridge Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Poynter Fellowship (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rhodesian Scholarships (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Legion Hall, University College of Ghana (Legon, Accra, W. Africa) (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
- Records of Robin Winks, 1953-1981; Accession 1988-A-081
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016
  - Announcements and Correspondence
    - 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Summer Fellowships
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Master's Speeches and Letters, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Master's Report, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Berkeley Press, 1953-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Social Planning, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Strike Memo, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Royal Visit, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Administrative records documenting life at Berkeley College, 1934-1983; Accession 1988-A-099
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  - Adult Education Program, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aide-Staff Suggestions, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arts Festival, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art Workshop, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Berkeley Broadside" (Newsletter), 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Berkeley Christmas Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Berkeley College Council, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley Crew, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Berkeley Library, 1935-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Berkeley Library Reports, 1936-1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gifts to Berkeley Library, 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Berkeley Literary Magazines, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Berkeley Lounge-Swiss Faience Stove (Correspondence), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Berkeley Memorabilia Committee, 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Berkeley Players: Correspondence, 1947-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15-19)
  - Berkeley Players-Bill Francis Costume Designs for Epicaene, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Berkeley Players:
    - Notebook, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Programs, 1939-1959 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Programs, 1959-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Berkeley Snack Bar, 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bishop Berkeley Folios, 1938-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bishop Berkeley Letter, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - College Weekend, 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Commonplace Society, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Coyle Speaking Contest, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Directories, 1954-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Dunster House-Harvard, 1951-1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "High Street Herald" (Newsletter), 1949-1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Kent Arnold-Harry Evans Memorial Foundation, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Master's Advisory Council
    - 1945-1949 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - 1960-1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - May Day, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Music, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Music (Berkeley-Calhoun Bach Society), 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Music Room, 1952-1963 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Newspaper Clippings about Berkeley, 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Palio Banners, 1934-1963 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Parents' Day
    - 1955-1959 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Pool Room, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Portrait of George Dudley Seymour (in Master's Office), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Proposed Courses in Berkeley, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Reports to the President, 1935-1970 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Residential Colleges, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Rules of Berkeley College, 1948-1965 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Social Events, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Student Advisory Board, 1951-1966 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Yale Heidelberg Scholarships, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Berkeley Scrapbook Photos, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1940s (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Parents' Day, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Photographs of Thomas C. Mendenhall (Berkeley Master), 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Various Berkeley Rooms, taken by Mr. Street for Alumni Magazine, 1957 December (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
    - Parents' Day, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - The Social Scene, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Woodworking Shop, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Bishop Berkeley's Mitre, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Undergraduate Arts Festival, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Slides of Swiss Faience Stove, taken by David Richards, 1965 July (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Exterior Photographs, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 69-70)
    - Mendenhall Balcony Scene, Mendenhall Dinner, undated; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Records, circa 1968-1990; Accession 1991-A-015
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025
  - "Berkeley Broadsides", 1968-1989 (Box 1)
  - "Berkeley-in-the-News", 1981-1986 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Requests for make-up exams, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Gordon Grand Fellowship, 1982-1990 (Box 2)
  - Dramat, 1973-1984 (Box 2)
  - Financial, 1972-1987 (Box 2)
  - Financial, 1968-1987 (Box 3)
  - Council of Masters, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Council of Masters, 1983-1990 (Box 4)
  - Alumni, 1975-1988 (Box 4)
  - Honorary Degree, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Commonplace Society, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
  - Commencement, 1980-1984 (Box 4)
  - Master's Tea Invitations, 1980-1988 (Box 4)